Long ago, the legend says,
Chang’e flew to the Moon.
Unable to return home.
In 726, Li Bai looked up at the Moon
and wrote about missing home.
Every space program on Earth
is building the International Moonbase.
The willow in winter is slender,
her switches plain and straight;
the West Lake wind sings over water,
like smoothing silk, and late
in afternoon teahouses watching
snow-brewed tea. That line—
I raise my cup to invite the bright moon;
with my shadow, we make three.
I think of you — homesick with waning
moons and lonely wine.
The moon wanes, the wine grows cold —
I miss you.
I think of you, I think of you
I raise my cup to invite the bright moon
moons and lonely wine
I raise my head to gaze at the bright moon
I lower my head and think of home.
The bright moon rises over the sea;
however far apart, we share this moment.
For everyone working far from
the people they love.
Look up — they’re looking
at the same moon.